I started my journey 30 years ago.
بدأت رحلتي منذ ثلاثين سنة
And I worked in mines. And I realized that
وعملت في المناجم وأدركت أن
this was a world unseen.
هذا العالم غير مرئي.
And I wanted, through color and large format cameras
وأردت -- من خلال الألوان وكاميرات التصوير الكبيرة
and very large prints,
والصور المطبوعة الكبيرة الحجم --
to make a body of work that somehow
أن أنتج أعمالا
became symbols of our
تصبح بشكل ما رموزا لكيفية
use of the landscape,
استخدامنا لمناطقنا الطبيعية
how we use the land.
ولكيفية استخدامنا للأراضي.
And to me this was
وكان هذا بالنسبة لي
a key component that somehow, through this medium of photography,
عنصرا أساسيا حيث أننا٬ ومن خلال التصوير الفوتوغرافي٬
which allows us to contemplate these landscapes,
نستطيع أن نتأمل هذه الأراضي٬
that I thought photography was perfectly suited
وظننت أن التصوير الفوتوغرافي ملائم تماما
to doing this type of work.
من أجل هذا النوع من العمل.
And after 17 years of photographing large industrial landscapes,
بعد 17 سنة من تصوير الأراضي الصناعية الكبيرة
it occurred to me that
أدركت أن
oil is underpinning the scale and speed.
النفط يشكل الأساس في مستوى وسرعة --
Because that is what has changed,
لأن هذا الذي تغير --
is the speed at which we're taking all our resources.
سرعتنا في استهلاك مواردنا.
And so then I went out to develop a whole series
فخرجت لتطوير سلسلة كاملة
on the landscape of oil.
تتمحور على أراضي النفط.
And what I want to do is to kind of map an arc
وما أردت فعله هو أن أرسم خريطة قوس
that there is extraction, where we're taking it from the ground,
للإستخراج٬ ومكان الإستخراج
refinement. And that's one chapter.
والتكرير. وهذا كله عبارة عن فصلٍ واحد.
The other chapter that I wanted to look at was
الفصل الٱخر الذي أردت تفحصه هو
how we use it -- our cities,
كيفية استخدامنا للنفط -- مدننا٬
our cars, our motorcultures,
سياراتنا٬ وثقافة المحركات خاصتنا
where people gather around the vehicle
حيث يتجمع الناس حول المركبة
as a celebration.
للإحتفال.
And then the third one is this idea of the end of oil,
والفصل الثالث هو فكرة نهاية النفط هذه٬
this entropic end,
هذه النهاية الحتمية --
where all of our parts of cars, our tires,
حيث كل سياراتنا٬ دواليب سياراتنا٬
oil filters,
مصافي الزيت٬
helicopters, planes --
المروحيات٬ الطائرات --
where are the landscapes where all of that stuff ends up?
في أي أراضٍ سينتهي بها الأمر؟
And to me, again, photography was
ومجددا٬ كان التصوير الفوتوغرافي بالنسبة لي
a way in which I could explore and research the world,
طريقة تمكنني من استكشاف ودراسة العالم
and find those places.
وايجاد هذه المناطق.
And another idea that I had as well,
والفكرة الأخرى التي خطرت لي أيضا
that was brought forward by an ecologist --
والتي جاء بها عالم بيئي --
he basically did a calculation where
حيث قام بإجراء حساب
he took one liter of gas and said,
أخذ فيه ليتراً من الغاز وسأل:
well, how much carbon it would take, and how much organic material?
"حسنا٬ كم تستلزم هذه من مادة الكاربون٬ وكم من المواد العضوية؟"
It was 23 metric tons for one liter.
والجواب كان 23 طن متري للّيتر الواحد.
So whenever I fill up my gas,
لذا كلما أقوم بتعبئة الغاز٬
I think of that liter, and how much carbon.
أفكر بذلك الليتر٬ وكمية الكاربون الذي استلزمته.
And I know that oil comes from the ocean and phytoplankton,
وأنا أعلم أن النفط يأتي من المحيط والنباتات البحرية الطائفة
but he did the calculations for our Earth
ولكنه قام بإجراء الحسابات لكوكبنا
and what it had to do to produce that amount of energy.
وما فعلته لإنتاج تلك الكمية من الطاقة.
From the photosynthetic growth,
من جهة النمو النباتي الضوئي٬
it would take 500 years of that growth
فإنها تتطلب 500 سنة من ذلك النمو
to produce what we use, the 30 billion barrels we use per year.
لإنتاج ما نستخدمه٬ أي 30 مليار برميل في السنة.
And that also brought me to the fact that
وهذا أيضا لفت إنتباهي لطبيعة
this poses such a risk to our society.
الخطر الذي يواجه مجتمعنا.
Looking at 30 billion per year,
عندما ننظر إلى 30 مليار برميل في السنة
we look at our two largest suppliers,
فإننا ننظر إلى اثنين من أكبر موّردينا
Saudi Arabia and now Canada, with its dirty oil.
وهما السعودية٬ والٱن كندا بنفطها الوسخ.
And together they only form about 15 years of supply.
كلاهما معا يشكلان 15 سنة من التزويد.
The whole world, at 1.2 trillion estimated reserves,
العالم كله بكمية احتياطه المقدرة ب1.2 تريليون
only gives us about 45 years.
يعطينا حوالي 45 سنة فقط.
So, it's not a question of if, but a question of when
لذا هي ليست مسألة "إذا"٬ هي مسألة "متى"
peak oil will come upon us.
ستأتي علينا الذروة النفطية.
So, to me, using photography --
لذا فإن استخدام التصوير الفوتوغرافي٬ بالنسبة لي --
and I feel that all of us need to now begin to really
وأظن أننا الٱن يجب علينا أن نبدأ
take the task of using our talents,
بالعمل لإستخدام مواهبنا
our ways of thinking,
وطرق تفكيرنا
to begin to deal with what I think is probably
من أجل التعامل مع ما أظنه
one of the most challenging issues of our time,
أكثر القضايا صعوبة في عصرنا
how to deal with our energy crisis.
وهي كيفية التعامل مع أزمة الطاقة.
And I would like to say that, on the other side of it,
وأود أن أقول أن من جهة أخرى
30, 40 years from now, the children that I have,
30 أو 40 سنة من الٱن٬ أي مع أولادنا٬
I can look at them and say, "We did everything
يمكنني أن أنظر إليهم وأن أقول: "لقد فعلنا كل شيء
we possibly, humanly could do,
استطعنا فعله وبذلنا قصارى جهدنا
to begin to mitigate this,
من أجل البدء بتخفيف هذا٬
what I feel is one of the most important and critical
وهو ما أظنه من أهم وأخطر
moments in our time. Thank you.
الأوقات في عصرنا." شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)